<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>social change on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/social-change/</link><description>Recent content in social change on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/social-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>Google Plus: Nonprofit and social change implications</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</guid><description>
While this presentation does not cover the basics of what Google Plus is and how it works, it looks at how nonprofits and activists might effectively use Google Plus and highlights its most useful tools. The presentation also discusses the effects that Google Plus's approach to social networking might have on online activism in general.</description></item><item><title>Too few women in tech? Blame sexism.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</guid><description>
Sexism is bigger than any one person; it's a system in which our entire society is enmeshed. Too often, such systematic discrimination as treated as discrete, individual acts, disconnected from the larger reality. What too many men miss is the reality that the system under which they face such inhumane expectations is the same one that limits the potential of women. This exists in the technology and nonprofit tech communities no less than the rest of society — and has to be faced in a systematic way, not simply by counting the number of women on a tech panel.</description></item><item><title>What online activism can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Online activism didn’t come out of nowhere. The methods and tactics of online activists -- be they individuals or international nonprofits with hundreds of staff -- are drawn on social change movements and community organizing strategies that have been tried, experimented with, failed, tweaked, and tried again, long before the Internet existed.</description></item><item><title>Finding the movement's voice: Online social networks and social change</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</guid><description>
The subtitle of this could be, “Social change has always relied on social networks -- they just weren’t called Facebook.”</description></item><item><title>Social change takes more than social media</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/05/social-change-takes-more-than-social-media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/05/social-change-takes-more-than-social-media/</guid><description>
Social media doesn't mean you do less organizing -- it means you (can) do it better, or at least differently. You still have to use all the old skills of coalition-building, strategic planning, creative social action, managing relationships and preventing burnout. None of that goes away just because you’re engaging with people on Facebook instead of in town halls.</description></item><item><title>The fire and the food: Why there's no such thing as a Twitter revolution</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</guid><description>
If organizers limit themselves to seeing Twitter as a strategy in and of itself -- without considering the strategy apart from the tool -- they risk overlooking ways to run a more effective campaign on other platforms, or augmenting a campaign using multiple platforms. Worse, organizers risk giving supporters feel-good activism that quenches their desire for social change without actually moving the movement closer to a concrete goal, or putting any pressure on powerholders.</description></item><item><title>Using Facebook for social change: The webinar</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</guid><description>
Just a quick note to say I’ll be speaking as part of Social Actions' 'Using Facebook for Social Change' webinar on Thursday, along with Susan Gordon, the nonprofit coordinator of Causes, and moderated by Beth Pickard and David Karp of Firstgiving: 'You’re invited to join in a live and open text chat to discuss how you can use Facebook for social change. This is your opportunity to share experiences and ask questions about how people and orgs can do outreach, inspire action, and fund raise on the Facebook network.'</description></item><item><title>Using Social Networks for Social Change: Facebook, MySpace and More</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</guid><description>
In this presentation from the Democracy in Action Community Conference 2008, I talk about some of the successful approaches for nonprofits in using social networks like Facebook and MySpace, and social media like Flickr and YouTube. I give detailed examples of how the Genocide Intervention Network, where I served as director of communications and Internet strategy coordinator for four years, used social networking to achieve its goals in membership development, advocacy and fundraising.</description></item></channel></rss>