<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>social change on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/social-change/</link><description>Recent content in social change on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/social-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>Too few women in tech? Blame sexism.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</guid><description>
Sexism is bigger than any one person; it's a system in which our entire society is enmeshed. Too often, such systematic discrimination as treated as discrete, individual acts, disconnected from the larger reality. What too many men miss is the reality that the system under which they face such inhumane expectations is the same one that limits the potential of women. This exists in the technology and nonprofit tech communities no less than the rest of society — and has to be faced in a systematic way, not simply by counting the number of women on a tech panel.</description></item><item><title>What online activism can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Online activism didn’t come out of nowhere. The methods and tactics of online activists -- be they individuals or international nonprofits with hundreds of staff -- are drawn on social change movements and community organizing strategies that have been tried, experimented with, failed, tweaked, and tried again, long before the Internet existed.</description></item><item><title>Finding the movement's voice: Online social networks and social change</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</guid><description>
The subtitle of this could be, “Social change has always relied on social networks -- they just weren’t called Facebook.”</description></item></channel></rss>