<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>online advocacy on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/categories/online-advocacy/</link><description>Recent content in online advocacy on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/categories/online-advocacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>What online activism can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Online activism didn’t come out of nowhere. The methods and tactics of online activists -- be they individuals or international nonprofits with hundreds of staff -- are drawn on social change movements and community organizing strategies that have been tried, experimented with, failed, tweaked, and tried again, long before the Internet existed.</description></item><item><title>Government accountability through web 2.0: A case study</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</guid><description>
Last week, Special Envoy to Sudan Gen. Scott Gration sat down with representatives from Save Darfur and the student network STAND for an unprecedented live Q&amp;A, webcast directly from the White House website. The webcast was notable not just for its interactivity -- members of both STAND and Save Darfur were encouraged to submit questions, which were then asked directly of Gration on air -- but for its accountability.</description></item><item><title>NetSquared project interviews and session notes</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/netsquared-project-interviews-session-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/netsquared-project-interviews-session-notes/</guid><description>
Some really incredible presentations here at the NetSquared conference, both from featured projects and individual speakers. Seth Horwitz and I are busily collecting information for next Tuesday's Philly NetSquared event.</description></item><item><title>Hundreds gather for social change tech at NetSquared Year Three</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/hundreds-gather-social-change-tech-netsquared-year-three/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/hundreds-gather-social-change-tech-netsquared-year-three/</guid><description>
The NetSquared Year Three conference has gotten off to a great start: Nonprofit staffers, activists, techies and funders gathering to talk about -- and award some money to -- using technology for social change.</description></item><item><title>Organizing rather than mobilizing: Using social networks for constituency-building</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/10/organizing-rather-than-mobilizing-using-social-networks-constituency-building/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/10/organizing-rather-than-mobilizing-using-social-networks-constituency-building/</guid><description>
For the Genocide Intervention Network, involvement in the "social web" is really an outgrowth of our entire mission: To form the first anti-genocide constituency, and to empower our members with the tools to prevent and stop genocide. The words "constituency" and "empower" are key. We want an educated, active movement of people interested in preventing and stopping genocide. Our members need to be able to think for themselves on the issue, not to simply be another name on a list, but to be a hub in an ever-expanding network.</description></item><item><title>Notes from NTC: Participatory media and the future of online outreach</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/04/notes-ntc-participatory-media-future-online-outreach/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/04/notes-ntc-participatory-media-future-online-outreach/</guid><description>
Although these two panels -- "Leveraging the Power of Participatory Media" and "The Future of Online Outreach" -- were held separately at the 2007 Nonprofit Technology Conference, I thought that they related so well that I’d present them together.</description></item></channel></rss>