<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drupalcon Portland 2013 on Rootwork.org</title>
    <link>https://rootwork.org/series/drupalcon-portland-2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drupalcon Portland 2013 on Rootwork.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.org/series/drupalcon-portland-2013/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We need to talk about your stylesheets: An interview with Jonathan Snook at Drupalcon Portland</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/we-need-talk-about-your-stylesheets-interview-jonathan-snook-drupalcon-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/we-need-talk-about-your-stylesheets-interview-jonathan-snook-drupalcon-portland/</guid>
      <description>SMACSS, or Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS, was developed by Jonathan Snook, a featured speaker at Drupalcon Portland. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to get the opportunity to have Jonathan speak, not only because of my personally well-dog-eared copy of SMACSS, but because Drupal itself is adopting a SMACSS approach to its CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupalcon Portland: Responsive web design in a snap with Breakpoint and Sass</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupalcon-portland-responsive-web-design-snap-breakpoint-sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupalcon-portland-responsive-web-design-snap-breakpoint-sass/</guid>
      <description>Media queries are a key part of responsive web design, because they control at what width (among other things) different CSS rules kick in. &amp;ldquo;Breakpoint makes writing media queries in Sass super simple,&amp;rdquo; say Mason Wendell and Sam Richard, creators of the extension to Compass, and they&amp;rsquo;re right. It&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that we&amp;rsquo;d want them to present at Drupalcon, since design in Drupal, like web design everywhere, has been embracing responsive web design as a fundamental principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal 8 and the power of Twig: A Drupalcon Portland featured session</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-power-twig-drupalcon-portland-featured-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-power-twig-drupalcon-portland-featured-session/</guid>
      <description>A new theming engine, Twig, is coming along with Drupal 8&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the Symfony framework. And it&amp;rsquo;s downright magical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal 8, aural interfaces and groundbreaking accessibility at Drupalcon Portland</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-aural-interfaces-groundbreaking-accessibility-drupalcon-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-aural-interfaces-groundbreaking-accessibility-drupalcon-portland/</guid>
      <description>Drupal is getting a switchboard operator! Module developers will be able to pass a string to a method called &amp;ldquo;announce&amp;rdquo; on the Drupal object and have that string read by a screen reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow your own: Learning custom base themes at Drupalcon Portland</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/grow-your-own-learning-custom-base-themes-drupalcon-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/grow-your-own-learning-custom-base-themes-drupalcon-portland/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;By necessity, base themes make assumptions about how teams and
individuals work. By rolling your own, you&amp;rsquo;ll become much more comfortable
and
informed about the Drupal theming layer, and have a better launchpad for
your
front-end projects.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninjas in your code at Drupalcon Portland: Sass with extends and placeholders</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/ninjas-your-code-drupalcon-portland-sass-extends-placeholders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/ninjas-your-code-drupalcon-portland-sass-extends-placeholders/</guid>
      <description>Dale Sande captures the revolution in efficiency that Sass brings, and at Drupalcon Portland he&amp;rsquo;s taking us way past Sass basics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A world-class frontend track at Drupalcon Portland</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/world-class-frontend-track-drupalcon-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/world-class-frontend-track-drupalcon-portland/</guid>
      <description>The big news at Drupalcon Portland is that, for the first time at a Drupalcon, we&amp;rsquo;re having separate frontend and user experience (UX) tracks. That means we were able to offer even more sessions targeted directly at frontend developers, and as the local track chair for frontend, I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about what we&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontend session proposals to Portland Drupalcon due today!</title>
      <link>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/frontend-session-proposals-portland-drupalcon-due-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/frontend-session-proposals-portland-drupalcon-due-today/</guid>
      <description>As the local track chair for the frontend track, I&amp;rsquo;m posting this to encourage any last-minute session proposals bouncing around in your head to get typed out and proposed today. That&amp;rsquo;s right: Today&amp;rsquo;s the Portland Drupalcon session proposal deadline. Submit your proposal now! (And yes, nonprofit and nonprofit developer friends, there’s an NGO track too.)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
