<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nonprofit technology on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/categories/nonprofit-technology/</link><description>Recent content in nonprofit technology on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/categories/nonprofit-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>Free Drupal Q&amp;A call for nonprofits and social change tomorrow, Feb. 28</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</guid><description>
Tomorrow at 1PM Eastern/10AM Pacific, Johanna Bates and I will be co-hosting the monthly Nonprofit Drupal Community of Practice discussion and Q&amp;A call. This is a free conference call, sponsored by the Nonprofit Technology Network (NTEN) but open to anyone. Please join us!</description></item><item><title>Domain Registry of America is a scam. Don't let your nonprofit get fooled.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</guid><description>
Domain Registry of America sends the owner of a website domain an official-looking “expiration notice,” urging the owner to “act today” to prevent “loss of your online identity making it difficult for your customers and friends to locate you.” Yet Domain Registry of America vastly overcharges for domain registration — their entire business model is built on swindling people into switching their registration. Don’t let it happen to you!</description></item><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what’s being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>Facebook removes default landing tab for new nonprofit pages</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</guid><description>
Now all visitors to a nonprofit's Facebook Page will be directed to the Wall. What's more, with tabs being de-emphasized by their move to smaller links under your profile, it's less obvious how new visitors can find out more about your organization.</description></item><item><title>Too few women in tech? Blame sexism.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</guid><description>
Sexism is bigger than any one person; it's a system in which our entire society is enmeshed. Too often, such systematic discrimination as treated as discrete, individual acts, disconnected from the larger reality. What too many men miss is the reality that the system under which they face such inhumane expectations is the same one that limits the potential of women. This exists in the technology and nonprofit tech communities no less than the rest of society — and has to be faced in a systematic way, not simply by counting the number of women on a tech panel.</description></item><item><title>Causes abandons 184,674 nonprofit supporters on MySpace</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/causes-abandons-184-674-nonprofit-supporters-myspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/causes-abandons-184-674-nonprofit-supporters-myspace/</guid><description>
To Causes, leaving MySpace to focus on its core community on Facebook made good business sense, but certainly those organizations left in the lurch on MySpace feel otherwise. Simply put, you can’t rely on third-party, often for-profit services to support your organization’s interests. What would it look like if nonprofits and social change movements -- which these third party applications often use to market themselves as effective and "good" -- started demanding some openness?</description></item><item><title>Finding the movement's voice: Online social networks and social change</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</guid><description>
The subtitle of this could be, “Social change has always relied on social networks -- they just weren’t called Facebook.”</description></item></channel></rss>