<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nonprofit technology on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/categories/nonprofit-technology/</link><description>Recent content in nonprofit technology on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/categories/nonprofit-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>Free Drupal Q&amp;A call for nonprofits and social change tomorrow, Feb. 28</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</guid><description>
Tomorrow at 1PM Eastern/10AM Pacific, Johanna Bates and I will be co-hosting the monthly Nonprofit Drupal Community of Practice discussion and Q&amp;A call. This is a free conference call, sponsored by the Nonprofit Technology Network (NTEN) but open to anyone. Please join us!</description></item><item><title>Domain Registry of America is a scam. Don't let your nonprofit get fooled.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</guid><description>
Domain Registry of America sends the owner of a website domain an official-looking “expiration notice,” urging the owner to “act today” to prevent “loss of your online identity making it difficult for your customers and friends to locate you.” Yet Domain Registry of America vastly overcharges for domain registration — their entire business model is built on swindling people into switching their registration. Don’t let it happen to you!</description></item><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what’s being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>Google Plus: Nonprofit and social change implications</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</guid><description>
While this presentation does not cover the basics of what Google Plus is and how it works, it looks at how nonprofits and activists might effectively use Google Plus and highlights its most useful tools. The presentation also discusses the effects that Google Plus's approach to social networking might have on online activism in general.</description></item><item><title>Facebook removes default landing tab for new nonprofit pages</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</guid><description>
Now all visitors to a nonprofit's Facebook Page will be directed to the Wall. What's more, with tabs being de-emphasized by their move to smaller links under your profile, it's less obvious how new visitors can find out more about your organization.</description></item><item><title>Too few women in tech? Blame sexism.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</guid><description>
Sexism is bigger than any one person; it's a system in which our entire society is enmeshed. Too often, such systematic discrimination as treated as discrete, individual acts, disconnected from the larger reality. What too many men miss is the reality that the system under which they face such inhumane expectations is the same one that limits the potential of women. This exists in the technology and nonprofit tech communities no less than the rest of society — and has to be faced in a systematic way, not simply by counting the number of women on a tech panel.</description></item><item><title>Causes abandons 184,674 nonprofit supporters on MySpace</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/causes-abandons-184-674-nonprofit-supporters-myspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/causes-abandons-184-674-nonprofit-supporters-myspace/</guid><description>
To Causes, leaving MySpace to focus on its core community on Facebook made good business sense, but certainly those organizations left in the lurch on MySpace feel otherwise. Simply put, you can’t rely on third-party, often for-profit services to support your organization’s interests. What would it look like if nonprofits and social change movements -- which these third party applications often use to market themselves as effective and "good" -- started demanding some openness?</description></item><item><title>Finding the movement's voice: Online social networks and social change</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</guid><description>
The subtitle of this could be, “Social change has always relied on social networks -- they just weren’t called Facebook.”</description></item><item><title>Gurus are not enough: A call for organizers and organizing in social media</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/09/gurus-are-not-enough-call-organizers-organizing-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/09/gurus-are-not-enough-call-organizers-organizing-social-media/</guid><description>
Gurus, mavens and experts convey information — they tell you the way things are. Organizers, conversely, cultivate leadership and facilitate a community's exploration of its vision — they offer a way to see how things could be.</description></item><item><title>The fire and the food: Why there's no such thing as a Twitter revolution</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</guid><description>
If organizers limit themselves to seeing Twitter as a strategy in and of itself -- without considering the strategy apart from the tool -- they risk overlooking ways to run a more effective campaign on other platforms, or augmenting a campaign using multiple platforms. Worse, organizers risk giving supporters feel-good activism that quenches their desire for social change without actually moving the movement closer to a concrete goal, or putting any pressure on powerholders.</description></item><item><title>Using Facebook for social change: The webinar</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</guid><description>
Just a quick note to say I’ll be speaking as part of Social Actions' 'Using Facebook for Social Change' webinar on Thursday, along with Susan Gordon, the nonprofit coordinator of Causes, and moderated by Beth Pickard and David Karp of Firstgiving: 'You’re invited to join in a live and open text chat to discuss how you can use Facebook for social change. This is your opportunity to share experiences and ask questions about how people and orgs can do outreach, inspire action, and fund raise on the Facebook network.'</description></item><item><title>Community blogs run better on open-source software</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/01/community-blogs-run-better-open-source-software/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/01/community-blogs-run-better-open-source-software/</guid><description>
Even if Bryght/Acquia/May First went out of business tomorrow, virtually all of its customers could find another vendor to take their system completely intact and get them up and running in an hour or two.</description></item><item><title>Using social networks for social change: Facebook, MySpace and more</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</guid><description>
In this presentation from the Democracy in Action Community Conference 2008, I talk about some of the successful approaches for nonprofits in using social networks like Facebook and MySpace, and social media like Flickr and YouTube. I give detailed examples of how the Genocide Intervention Network, where I served as director of communications and Internet strategy coordinator for four years, used social networking to achieve its goals in membership development, advocacy and fundraising.</description></item><item><title>NetSquared project interviews and session notes</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/netsquared-project-interviews-session-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/netsquared-project-interviews-session-notes/</guid><description>
Some really incredible presentations here at the NetSquared conference, both from featured projects and individual speakers. Seth Horwitz and I are busily collecting information for next Tuesday's Philly NetSquared event.</description></item><item><title>Hundreds gather for social change tech at NetSquared Year Three</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/hundreds-gather-social-change-tech-netsquared-year-three/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/hundreds-gather-social-change-tech-netsquared-year-three/</guid><description>
The NetSquared Year Three conference has gotten off to a great start: Nonprofit staffers, activists, techies and funders gathering to talk about -- and award some money to -- using technology for social change.</description></item><item><title>Just what kind of social change are you interested in?</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/just-what-kind-social-change-are-you-interested/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/just-what-kind-social-change-are-you-interested/</guid><description>
Some nonprofits, older and more institutionalized, are wary of giving their members "control" of their "message" in social media. Mostly, I think that’s nothing more than a fear of losing power. When you think you know how to change the world, it can be hard for some people to want to involve others. But the message to nonprofits seems pretty clear: Stand in our way, and we’ll just go around you.</description></item><item><title>Organizing rather than mobilizing: Using social networks for constituency-building</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/10/organizing-rather-than-mobilizing-using-social-networks-constituency-building/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/10/organizing-rather-than-mobilizing-using-social-networks-constituency-building/</guid><description>
For the Genocide Intervention Network, involvement in the "social web" is really an outgrowth of our entire mission: To form the first anti-genocide constituency, and to empower our members with the tools to prevent and stop genocide. The words "constituency" and "empower" are key. We want an educated, active movement of people interested in preventing and stopping genocide. Our members need to be able to think for themselves on the issue, not to simply be another name on a list, but to be a hub in an ever-expanding network.</description></item><item><title>One minute for 1-800-GENOCIDE</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/07/one-minute-1-800-genocide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/07/one-minute-1-800-genocide/</guid><description>
Just wanted to highlight a small initiative the Genocide Intervention Network sent out today using Collactive, a web firm that helps organizations use their network of members to promote news stories and websites to larger audiences. In this case, we are asking our members to vote up an article on our anti-genocide hotline, 1-800-GENOCIDE.</description></item><item><title>Notes from NTC: Participatory media and the future of online outreach</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/04/notes-ntc-participatory-media-future-online-outreach/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2007/04/notes-ntc-participatory-media-future-online-outreach/</guid><description>
Although these two panels -- "Leveraging the Power of Participatory Media" and "The Future of Online Outreach" -- were held separately at the 2007 Nonprofit Technology Conference, I thought that they related so well that I’d present them together.</description></item><item><title>The theory of bottom-up social networking</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2006/12/theory-bottom-up-social-networking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2006/12/theory-bottom-up-social-networking/</guid><description>
Offering concrete ideas for how to solve a seemingly insurmountable problem can give people a sense that they, as individuals, have a stake in an issue. This sort of advocacy is similar to bottom-up, open-source collaborative projects like Wikipedia, in which no one group has proprietary ownership over an idea or a product; instead, the goal is a constant generation of awareness and ideas. Social media can be "a tool for mobilizing people for different kinds of action."</description></item></channel></rss>