<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rootwork.org blog on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Rootwork.org blog on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join me at the Devsigner conference in Portland this May: Designers and developers join forces!</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/04/join-me-devsigner-conference-portland-may-designers-developers-join-forces/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/04/join-me-devsigner-conference-portland-may-designers-developers-join-forces/</guid><description>
Devsigner is celebrating the cross-overs, the multi-disciplinarians, the coders who paint and the designers who send pull requests --- and those who want to develop some new left-right brain skills.</description></item><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>We need to talk about your stylesheets: An interview with Jonathan Snook at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/we-need-talk-about-your-stylesheets-interview-jonathan-snook-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/we-need-talk-about-your-stylesheets-interview-jonathan-snook-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
SMACSS, or Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS, was developed by Jonathan Snook, a featured speaker at Drupalcon Portland. I'm really excited to get the opportunity to have Jonathan speak, not only because of my personally well-dog-eared copy of SMACSS, but because Drupal itself is adopting a SMACSS approach to its CSS.</description></item><item><title>Drupalcon Portland: Responsive web design in a snap with Breakpoint and Sass</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupalcon-portland-responsive-web-design-snap-breakpoint-sass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupalcon-portland-responsive-web-design-snap-breakpoint-sass/</guid><description>
Media queries are a key part of responsive web design, because they control at what width (among other things) different CSS rules kick in. “Breakpoint makes writing media queries in Sass super simple,” say Mason Wendell and Sam Richard, creators of the extension to Compass, and they’re right. It’s not surprising that we’d want them to present at Drupalcon, since design in Drupal, like web design everywhere, has been embracing responsive web design as a fundamental principle.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 8 and the power of Twig: A Drupalcon Portland featured session</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-power-twig-drupalcon-portland-featured-session/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-power-twig-drupalcon-portland-featured-session/</guid><description>
A new theming engine, Twig, is coming along with Drupal 8’s adoption of the Symfony framework. And it’s downright magical.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 8, aural interfaces and groundbreaking accessibility at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-aural-interfaces-groundbreaking-accessibility-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-aural-interfaces-groundbreaking-accessibility-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
Drupal is getting a switchboard operator. Module developers will be able to pass a string to a method called "announce" on the Drupal object and have that string read by a screen reader.</description></item><item><title>Grow your own: Learning custom base themes at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/grow-your-own-learning-custom-base-themes-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/grow-your-own-learning-custom-base-themes-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
“By necessity, base themes make assumptions about how teams and individuals work. By rolling your own, you’ll become much more comfortable and informed about the Drupal theming layer, and have a better launchpad for your front-end projects.”</description></item><item><title>Ninjas in your code at Drupalcon Portland: Sass with extends and placeholders</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/ninjas-your-code-drupalcon-portland-sass-with-extends-placeholders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/ninjas-your-code-drupalcon-portland-sass-with-extends-placeholders/</guid><description>
Dale Sande captures the revolution in efficiency that Sass brings, and at Drupalcon Portland he's taking us way past Sass basics.</description></item><item><title>A world-class frontend track at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/world-class-frontend-track-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/world-class-frontend-track-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
The big news at Drupalcon Portland is that, for the first time at a Drupalcon, we’re having separate frontend and user experience (UX) tracks. That means we were able to offer even more sessions targeted directly at frontend developers, and as the local track chair for frontend, I’m really excited about what we’ve ended up with!</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>Free Drupal Q&amp;A call for nonprofits and social change tomorrow, Feb. 28</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</guid><description>
Tomorrow at 1PM Eastern/10AM Pacific, Johanna Bates and I will be co-hosting the monthly Nonprofit Drupal Community of Practice discussion and Q&amp;A call. This is a free conference call, sponsored by the Nonprofit Technology Network (NTEN) but open to anyone. Please join us!</description></item><item><title>Domain Registry of America is a scam. Don't let your nonprofit get fooled.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</guid><description>
Domain Registry of America sends the owner of a website domain an official-looking “expiration notice,” urging the owner to “act today” to prevent “loss of your online identity making it difficult for your customers and friends to locate you.” Yet Domain Registry of America vastly overcharges for domain registration — their entire business model is built on swindling people into switching their registration. Don’t let it happen to you!</description></item><item><title>Frontend session proposals to Portland Drupalcon due today!</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/frontend-session-proposals-portland-drupalcon-due-today/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/frontend-session-proposals-portland-drupalcon-due-today/</guid><description>
Summary</description></item><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what’s being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>A grant for your mission, as a poem</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/03/grant-your-mission-as-poem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/03/grant-your-mission-as-poem/</guid><description>
The Community TechKnowledge Foundation announced today a grant of $10,000 for a nonprofit that submits a description of their mission -- in the form of a poem. Along with the grant, the poetry will be turned into a song by Bill Dillon; there are also secondary prizes for $5,000, $1,000, and guitars autographed by members of Los Lonely Boys. The deadline is March 28.</description></item><item><title>Google Chrome for a cause, or, nonprofit deathmatch strikes again</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/google-chrome-cause-nonprofit-deathmatch-strikes-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/google-chrome-cause-nonprofit-deathmatch-strikes-again/</guid><description>
Summary</description></item></channel></rss>