<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rootwork.org blog on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Rootwork.org blog on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join me at the Devsigner conference in Portland this May: Designers and developers join forces!</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/04/join-me-devsigner-conference-portland-may-designers-developers-join-forces/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/04/join-me-devsigner-conference-portland-may-designers-developers-join-forces/</guid><description>
Devsigner is celebrating the cross-overs, the multi-disciplinarians, the coders who paint and the designers who send pull requests --- and those who want to develop some new left-right brain skills.</description></item><item><title>What online advocacy can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2014/03/online-advocacy-learn-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Investigate how sustainable social change has transpired in the past, and you’ll be closer to effecting change in the future.</description></item><item><title>We need to talk about your stylesheets: An interview with Jonathan Snook at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/we-need-talk-about-your-stylesheets-interview-jonathan-snook-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/we-need-talk-about-your-stylesheets-interview-jonathan-snook-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
SMACSS, or Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS, was developed by Jonathan Snook, a featured speaker at Drupalcon Portland. I'm really excited to get the opportunity to have Jonathan speak, not only because of my personally well-dog-eared copy of SMACSS, but because Drupal itself is adopting a SMACSS approach to its CSS.</description></item><item><title>Drupalcon Portland: Responsive web design in a snap with Breakpoint and Sass</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupalcon-portland-responsive-web-design-snap-breakpoint-sass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupalcon-portland-responsive-web-design-snap-breakpoint-sass/</guid><description>
Media queries are a key part of responsive web design, because they control at what width (among other things) different CSS rules kick in. “Breakpoint makes writing media queries in Sass super simple,” say Mason Wendell and Sam Richard, creators of the extension to Compass, and they’re right. It’s not surprising that we’d want them to present at Drupalcon, since design in Drupal, like web design everywhere, has been embracing responsive web design as a fundamental principle.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 8 and the power of Twig: A Drupalcon Portland featured session</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-power-twig-drupalcon-portland-featured-session/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-power-twig-drupalcon-portland-featured-session/</guid><description>
A new theming engine, Twig, is coming along with Drupal 8’s adoption of the Symfony framework. And it’s downright magical.</description></item><item><title>Drupal 8, aural interfaces and groundbreaking accessibility at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-aural-interfaces-groundbreaking-accessibility-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/drupal-8-aural-interfaces-groundbreaking-accessibility-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
Drupal is getting a switchboard operator. Module developers will be able to pass a string to a method called "announce" on the Drupal object and have that string read by a screen reader.</description></item><item><title>Grow your own: Learning custom base themes at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/grow-your-own-learning-custom-base-themes-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/grow-your-own-learning-custom-base-themes-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
“By necessity, base themes make assumptions about how teams and individuals work. By rolling your own, you’ll become much more comfortable and informed about the Drupal theming layer, and have a better launchpad for your front-end projects.”</description></item><item><title>Ninjas in your code at Drupalcon Portland: Sass with extends and placeholders</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/ninjas-your-code-drupalcon-portland-sass-with-extends-placeholders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/ninjas-your-code-drupalcon-portland-sass-with-extends-placeholders/</guid><description>
Dale Sande captures the revolution in efficiency that Sass brings, and at Drupalcon Portland he's taking us way past Sass basics.</description></item><item><title>A world-class frontend track at Drupalcon Portland</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/world-class-frontend-track-drupalcon-portland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/05/world-class-frontend-track-drupalcon-portland/</guid><description>
The big news at Drupalcon Portland is that, for the first time at a Drupalcon, we’re having separate frontend and user experience (UX) tracks. That means we were able to offer even more sessions targeted directly at frontend developers, and as the local track chair for frontend, I’m really excited about what we’ve ended up with!</description></item><item><title>Uncharitable: How businesses co-opt nonprofits and undermine their potential</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/04/uncharitable-how-businesses-co-opt-nonprofits-undermine-their-potential/</guid><description>
It’s no wonder Dan Pallotta is so popular among the TED crowd — business leaders and wealthy technologists who can see a product in every social trend. What’s more mystifying is why he would be popular among nonprofits, activists, and social changemakers, because it’s clear he has no substantive message for them.</description></item><item><title>Free Drupal Q&amp;A call for nonprofits and social change tomorrow, Feb. 28</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/free-drupal-qa-call-nonprofits-social-change-tomorrow-feb-28/</guid><description>
Tomorrow at 1PM Eastern/10AM Pacific, Johanna Bates and I will be co-hosting the monthly Nonprofit Drupal Community of Practice discussion and Q&amp;A call. This is a free conference call, sponsored by the Nonprofit Technology Network (NTEN) but open to anyone. Please join us!</description></item><item><title>Domain Registry of America is a scam. Don't let your nonprofit get fooled.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/domain-registry-america-scam-dont-let-your-nonprofit-get-fooled/</guid><description>
Domain Registry of America sends the owner of a website domain an official-looking “expiration notice,” urging the owner to “act today” to prevent “loss of your online identity making it difficult for your customers and friends to locate you.” Yet Domain Registry of America vastly overcharges for domain registration — their entire business model is built on swindling people into switching their registration. Don’t let it happen to you!</description></item><item><title>Frontend session proposals to Portland Drupalcon due today!</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/frontend-session-proposals-portland-drupalcon-due-today/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2013/02/frontend-session-proposals-portland-drupalcon-due-today/</guid><description>
Summary</description></item><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what’s being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>Google Plus: Nonprofit and social change implications</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</guid><description>
While this presentation does not cover the basics of what Google Plus is and how it works, it looks at how nonprofits and activists might effectively use Google Plus and highlights its most useful tools. The presentation also discusses the effects that Google Plus's approach to social networking might have on online activism in general.</description></item><item><title>A grant for your mission, as a poem</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/03/grant-your-mission-as-poem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/03/grant-your-mission-as-poem/</guid><description>
The Community TechKnowledge Foundation announced today a grant of $10,000 for a nonprofit that submits a description of their mission -- in the form of a poem. Along with the grant, the poetry will be turned into a song by Bill Dillon; there are also secondary prizes for $5,000, $1,000, and guitars autographed by members of Los Lonely Boys. The deadline is March 28.</description></item><item><title>Google Chrome for a cause, or, nonprofit deathmatch strikes again</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/google-chrome-cause-nonprofit-deathmatch-strikes-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/google-chrome-cause-nonprofit-deathmatch-strikes-again/</guid><description>
It's great that Google is directing money to nonprofits, and letting people decide where those donations go. But it's frustrating how Chrome for a Cause is rooted in a scarcity model — in which organizations must compete rather than collaborate.</description></item><item><title>Facebook removes default landing tab for new nonprofit pages</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</guid><description>
Now all visitors to a nonprofit's Facebook Page will be directed to the Wall. What's more, with tabs being de-emphasized by their move to smaller links under your profile, it's less obvious how new visitors can find out more about your organization.</description></item><item><title>Too few women in tech? Blame sexism.</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/08/too-few-women-tech-blame-sexism/</guid><description>
Sexism is bigger than any one person; it's a system in which our entire society is enmeshed. Too often, such systematic discrimination as treated as discrete, individual acts, disconnected from the larger reality. What too many men miss is the reality that the system under which they face such inhumane expectations is the same one that limits the potential of women. This exists in the technology and nonprofit tech communities no less than the rest of society — and has to be faced in a systematic way, not simply by counting the number of women on a tech panel.</description></item><item><title>What online activism can learn from community organizing</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/04/what-online-activism-can-learn-from-community-organizing/</guid><description>
Online activism didn’t come out of nowhere. The methods and tactics of online activists -- be they individuals or international nonprofits with hundreds of staff -- are drawn on social change movements and community organizing strategies that have been tried, experimented with, failed, tweaked, and tried again, long before the Internet existed.</description></item><item><title>Government accountability through web 2.0: A case study</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</guid><description>
Last week, Special Envoy to Sudan Gen. Scott Gration sat down with representatives from Save Darfur and the student network STAND for an unprecedented live Q&amp;A, webcast directly from the White House website. The webcast was notable not just for its interactivity -- members of both STAND and Save Darfur were encouraged to submit questions, which were then asked directly of Gration on air -- but for its accountability.</description></item><item><title>Causes abandons 184,674 nonprofit supporters on MySpace</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/causes-abandons-184-674-nonprofit-supporters-myspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/causes-abandons-184-674-nonprofit-supporters-myspace/</guid><description>
To Causes, leaving MySpace to focus on its core community on Facebook made good business sense, but certainly those organizations left in the lurch on MySpace feel otherwise. Simply put, you can’t rely on third-party, often for-profit services to support your organization’s interests. What would it look like if nonprofits and social change movements -- which these third party applications often use to market themselves as effective and "good" -- started demanding some openness?</description></item><item><title>Finding the movement's voice: Online social networks and social change</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/10/finding-movements-voice-online-social-networks-social-change/</guid><description>
The subtitle of this could be, “Social change has always relied on social networks -- they just weren’t called Facebook.”</description></item><item><title>Gurus Are Not Enough: A Call for Organizers and Organizing in Social Media</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/09/gurus-are-not-enough-call-organizers-organizing-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/09/gurus-are-not-enough-call-organizers-organizing-social-media/</guid><description>
Gurus, mavens and experts convey information — they tell you the way things are. Organizers, conversely, cultivate leadership and facilitate a community's exploration of its vision — they offer a way to see how things could be.</description></item><item><title>Social change takes more than social media</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/05/social-change-takes-more-than-social-media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/05/social-change-takes-more-than-social-media/</guid><description>
Social media doesn't mean you do less organizing -- it means you (can) do it better, or at least differently. You still have to use all the old skills of coalition-building, strategic planning, creative social action, managing relationships and preventing burnout. None of that goes away just because you’re engaging with people on Facebook instead of in town halls.</description></item><item><title>The fire and the food: Why there's no such thing as a Twitter revolution</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</guid><description>
If organizers limit themselves to seeing Twitter as a strategy in and of itself -- without considering the strategy apart from the tool -- they risk overlooking ways to run a more effective campaign on other platforms, or augmenting a campaign using multiple platforms. Worse, organizers risk giving supporters feel-good activism that quenches their desire for social change without actually moving the movement closer to a concrete goal, or putting any pressure on powerholders.</description></item><item><title>Using Facebook for social change: The webinar</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</guid><description>
Just a quick note to say I’ll be speaking as part of Social Actions' 'Using Facebook for Social Change' webinar on Thursday, along with Susan Gordon, the nonprofit coordinator of Causes, and moderated by Beth Pickard and David Karp of Firstgiving: 'You’re invited to join in a live and open text chat to discuss how you can use Facebook for social change. This is your opportunity to share experiences and ask questions about how people and orgs can do outreach, inspire action, and fund raise on the Facebook network.'</description></item><item><title>Community blogs run better on open-source software</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/01/community-blogs-run-better-open-source-software/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/01/community-blogs-run-better-open-source-software/</guid><description>
Even if Bryght/Acquia/May First went out of business tomorrow, virtually all of its customers could find another vendor to take their system completely intact and get them up and running in an hour or two.</description></item><item><title>Using Social Networks for Social Change: Facebook, MySpace and More</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</guid><description>
In this presentation from the Democracy in Action Community Conference 2008, I talk about some of the successful approaches for nonprofits in using social networks like Facebook and MySpace, and social media like Flickr and YouTube. I give detailed examples of how the Genocide Intervention Network, where I served as director of communications and Internet strategy coordinator for four years, used social networking to achieve its goals in membership development, advocacy and fundraising.</description></item><item><title>NetSquared project interviews and session notes</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/netsquared-project-interviews-session-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/netsquared-project-interviews-session-notes/</guid><description>
Some really incredible presentations here at the NetSquared conference, both from featured projects and individual speakers. Seth Horwitz and I are busily collecting information for next Tuesday's Philly NetSquared event.</description></item><item><title>Hundreds gather for social change tech at NetSquared Year Three</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/hundreds-gather-social-change-tech-netsquared-year-three/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/hundreds-gather-social-change-tech-netsquared-year-three/</guid><description>
The NetSquared Year Three conference has gotten off to a great start: Nonprofit staffers, activists, techies and funders gathering to talk about -- and award some money to -- using technology for social change.</description></item></channel></rss>