<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Twitter on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/twitter/</link><description>Recent content in Twitter on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what’s being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>Government accountability through web 2.0: A case study</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</guid><description>
Last week, Special Envoy to Sudan Gen. Scott Gration sat down with representatives from Save Darfur and the student network STAND for an unprecedented live Q&amp;A, webcast directly from the White House website. The webcast was notable not just for its interactivity -- members of both STAND and Save Darfur were encouraged to submit questions, which were then asked directly of Gration on air -- but for its accountability.</description></item><item><title>The fire and the food: Why there's no such thing as a Twitter revolution</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/04/fire-food-why-theres-no-such-thing-twitter-revolution/</guid><description>
If organizers limit themselves to seeing Twitter as a strategy in and of itself -- without considering the strategy apart from the tool -- they risk overlooking ways to run a more effective campaign on other platforms, or augmenting a campaign using multiple platforms. Worse, organizers risk giving supporters feel-good activism that quenches their desire for social change without actually moving the movement closer to a concrete goal, or putting any pressure on powerholders.</description></item><item><title>Using Social Networks for Social Change: Facebook, MySpace and More</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</guid><description>
In this presentation from the Democracy in Action Community Conference 2008, I talk about some of the successful approaches for nonprofits in using social networks like Facebook and MySpace, and social media like Flickr and YouTube. I give detailed examples of how the Genocide Intervention Network, where I served as director of communications and Internet strategy coordinator for four years, used social networking to achieve its goals in membership development, advocacy and fundraising.</description></item></channel></rss>