<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Archives: 2011 on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/</link><description>Recent content in Archives: 2011 on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what’s being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>Google Plus: Nonprofit and social change implications</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/08/google-plus-nonprofit-social-change-implications/</guid><description>
While this presentation does not cover the basics of what Google Plus is and how it works, it looks at how nonprofits and activists might effectively use Google Plus and highlights its most useful tools. The presentation also discusses the effects that Google Plus's approach to social networking might have on online activism in general.</description></item><item><title>A grant for your mission, as a poem</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/03/grant-your-mission-as-poem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/03/grant-your-mission-as-poem/</guid><description>
The Community TechKnowledge Foundation announced today a grant of $10,000 for a nonprofit that submits a description of their mission -- in the form of a poem. Along with the grant, the poetry will be turned into a song by Bill Dillon; there are also secondary prizes for $5,000, $1,000, and guitars autographed by members of Los Lonely Boys. The deadline is March 28.</description></item></channel></rss>