<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Facebook on Rootwork.org</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/facebook/</link><description>Recent content in Facebook on Rootwork.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two-click button foils Facebook tracking, a new tool for privacy-concerned nonprofits</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2011/09/two-click-button-foils-facebook-tracking-new-tool-privacy-concerned-nonprofits/</guid><description>
Organizations concerned about the privacy of their visitors should carefully weigh whether a given social widget is worth the risk in privacy. Moreover, these organizations should absolutely provide a privacy policy that specifically lays out what's being collected and by whom, and may also want to consider suggesting ways for those at risk to circumvent this data tracking.</description></item><item><title>Facebook removes default landing tab for new nonprofit pages</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2010/12/facebook-removes-default-landing-tab-new-nonprofit-pages/</guid><description>
Now all visitors to a nonprofit's Facebook Page will be directed to the Wall. What's more, with tabs being de-emphasized by their move to smaller links under your profile, it's less obvious how new visitors can find out more about your organization.</description></item><item><title>Government accountability through web 2.0: A case study</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/11/government-accountability-through-web-20-case-study/</guid><description>
Last week, Special Envoy to Sudan Gen. Scott Gration sat down with representatives from Save Darfur and the student network STAND for an unprecedented live Q&amp;A, webcast directly from the White House website. The webcast was notable not just for its interactivity -- members of both STAND and Save Darfur were encouraged to submit questions, which were then asked directly of Gration on air -- but for its accountability.</description></item><item><title>Using Facebook for social change: The webinar</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2009/02/using-facebook-social-change-webinar/</guid><description>
Just a quick note to say I'll be speaking as part of Social Actions' "Using Facebook for Social Change" webinar on Thursday, along with Susan Gordon, the nonprofit coordinator of Causes, and moderated by Beth Pickard and David Karp of Firstgiving: "You're invited to join in a live and open text chat to discuss how you can use Facebook for social change. This is your opportunity to share experiences and ask questions about how people and orgs can do outreach, inspire action, and fund raise on the Facebook network."</description></item><item><title>Using social networks for social change: Facebook, MySpace and more</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/10/using-social-networks-social-change-facebook-myspace-more/</guid><description>
In this presentation from the Democracy in Action Community Conference 2008, I talk about some of the successful approaches for nonprofits in using social networks like Facebook and MySpace, and social media like Flickr and YouTube. I give detailed examples of how the Genocide Intervention Network, where I served as director of communications and Internet strategy coordinator for four years, used social networking to achieve its goals in membership development, advocacy and fundraising.</description></item><item><title>Just what kind of social change are you interested in?</title><link>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/just-what-kind-social-change-are-you-interested/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rootwork.github.io/rootwork.org/blog/2008/05/just-what-kind-social-change-are-you-interested/</guid><description>
Some nonprofits, older and more institutionalized, are wary of giving their members "control" of their "message" in social media. Mostly, I think that's nothing more than a fear of losing power. When you think you know how to change the world, it can be hard for some people to want to involve others. But the message to nonprofits seems pretty clear: Stand in our way, and we'll just go around you.</description></item></channel></rss>